# Iustina Ivanova

♥ yustiks | in yustina-ivanova | ♦ yustiks.github.io | ✓ yustiks@gmail.com | +39.......

# SUMMARY

I apply Artificial Intelligence in real-world applications. My background is in software engineer: I am fascinated by computer vision and it's applications in the software solutions. Furthermore, I achieved with distinction a Master in Artificial Intelligence, where I researched neural networks for object detection. During the last three years, I conducted a research project about "Sensors and data for the analysis of sports activities (SALSA)", funded by the EFRE-FESR programme 2014-2020 (CUP: I56C19000110009), and published several well received papers about computer vision solutions and recommender systems web interfaces for sport climbers. Nowadays, I am focusing on vision-based methods and real applications where Artificial Intelligence can be used to improve the quality of life.

# Work Experience

### Artificial Intelligence developer

Nov 2022 - April 2022

During this four months short-term project, I developed a web-based solution which was designed to interact with Rest-API server (Kafka). I was employed in a project connected with the reconstruction of 3D human hearts.

### **Data Science Moderator**

May 2019 - Oct 2020

I designed and taught lectures 'Statistics' for students participating in a course 'Data science' in Netology. The lectures were given in Russian. The material is accessible online: https://github.com/yustinaivanova/Netology-statistics

### Computer Vision Data Scientist

April 2019 - Nov 2019

I worked as a data scientist in the railway company. We designed and deployed a video-based tracking system for people. The project aimed to, firstly, detect objects in the video, secondly, to detect people, and thirdly, to measure working time of a person from video data.

### Teacher of informatics, mathematics and physics

Aug 2013 - Nov 2017

- My tasks were to organize the study process and making the subjects to be interesting.
- I was preparing students for final exams in the high school EGE.
- As a result, around 30 students successfully passed exams, and entered to the universities.
- I prepared 10 students for programming competition.
- In addition, I gave lessons about website creation, and 2D game development.

## Projects

### Recommender System Website for Outdoor Sportclimbers

Link to Github

In this project, I developed several prototypes of websites which recommended sport climbers potentially interesting climbing place in Arco (Italy).

# EDUCATION

2022 - present	PhD (Computer Science) at University of Portsmouth, United Kingdom	
2019 - 2022	PhD (Computer Science) at Free University of Bolzano, Italy	
2017 - 2018	Master of Science (Artificial Intelligence) at University of Southampton, Unit	$\operatorname{ed}$
	Kingdom (Distinction	on)
2007 - 2013	Specialist (Software Engineering) at Bauman Moscow State Technical Universi	ty,
	Russia (3,8	/5)

# **PUBLICATIONS**

- Ivanova, Iustina, Marina Andrić, Sadaf Moaveninejad, et al. (2020). "Video and Sensor-Based Rope Pulling Detection in Sport Climbing". In: *Proceedings of the 3rd International Workshop on Multimedia Content Analysis in Sports.* MMSports '20. Seattle, WA, USA: Association for Computing Machinery, pp. 53–60. ISBN: 9781450381499. DOI: 10.1145/3422844.3423058. URL: https://doi.org/10.1145/3422844.3423058.
- Shtekhin, Sergey Evgenievich et al. (2020). "Computer vision system for working time estimation by human activities detection in video frames". In: *Proc. of the Institute for System Programming of the Russian Academy of Science* 32.1.
- Ivanova, Iustina (2021). "Climber Behavior Modeling and Recommendation". In: Proceedings of the 29th ACM Conference on User Modeling, Adaptation and Personalization. UMAP '21. Utrecht, Netherlands: Association for Computing Machinery, pp. 298–303. ISBN: 9781450383660. DOI: 10.1145/3450613.3459658. URL: https://doi.org/10.1145/3450613.3459658.
- Ivanova, Iustina, Marina Andric, Andrea Janes, et al. (2021). "Climbing Activity Recognition and Measurement with Sensor Data Analysis". In: Companion Publication of the 2020 International Conference on Multimodal Interaction. ICMI '20 Companion. Virtual Event, Netherlands: Association for Computing Machinery, pp. 245–249. ISBN: 9781450380027. DOI: 10.1145/3395035.3425303. URL: https://doi.org/10.1145/3395035.3425303.
- Ivanova, Iustina et al. (2021). "Knowledge-Based Recommendations for Climbers". eng. In: vol. 2960. CEUR Workshop Proceedings. CEUR-WS, p. 6.
- Andric, Marina et al. (2022). "Climbing Route Difficulty Grade Prediction and Explanation". In: *IEEE/WIC/ACM International Conference on Web Intelligence and Intelligent Agent Technology*. WI-IAT '21. Melbourne, VIC, Australia: Association for Computing Machinery, pp. 285–292. ISBN: 9781450391153. DOI: 10.1145/3486622.3493932. URL: https://doi.org/10.1145/3486622.3493932.
- Ivanova, Iustina et al. (2022). "Content-Based Recommendations for Crags and Climbing Routes". In: Information and Communication Technologies in Tourism 2022. Ed. by Jason L. Stienmetz et al. Cham: Springer International Publishing, pp. 369–381. ISBN: 978-3-030-94751-4.
- Ivanova, Iustina Alekseevna et al. (2022). "Map and Content-Based Climbing Recommender System". In: Adjunct Proceedings of the 30th ACM Conference on User Modeling, Adaptation and Personalization. UMAP '22 Adjunct. Barcelona, Spain: Association for Computing Machinery, pp. 41–45. ISBN: 9781450392327. DOI: 10.1145/3511047.3536416. URL: https://doi.org/10.1145/3511047.3536416.
- Ivanova, Iustina and Mike Wald (2023). "Recommender systems for outdoor adventure tourism sports: hiking, running and climbing". In: *Human-Centric Intelligent Systems*.
- Ivanova, Iustina Alekseevna and Mike Wald (2023a). "How can we model climbers' future visits from their past records?" In: Adjunct Proceedings of the 30th ACM Conference on User Modeling, Adaptation and Personalization. UMAP '23 Adjunct. Limassol, Cyprus: Association for Computing Machinery. DOI: 10.1145/3563359.3597408. URL: https://doi.org/10.1145/3563359.3597408.
- (2023b). "Introducing Context in Climbing Crags Recommender System in Arco, Italy". In: Companion Proceedings of the 28th International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces. IUI '23 Companion. Sydney, NSW, Australia: Association for Computing Machinery, pp. 12–15. ISBN: 9798400701078. DOI: 10.1145/3581754.3584120. URL: https://doi.org/10.1145/3581754.3584120.

# SKILLS

Programming Python, OpenCV, machine learning, computer vision, recommender systems,

Javascript, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Git

Professional Softwares VScode, PyCharm, Jupyter Notebook, Docker, React, Bootstrap, Flask

# Courses and Schools

3rd Advanced Course on Data Science & Machine Learning. (Siena, Italy). July 13-17, 2020

Summer school for data science as part of PhD study.

4th International School on Deep Learning. (Canary Island, Spain). July 26-30, 2021

Deep learning summer school as part of PhD study

Big Sports Data Science School. (Caen, France).

June 27-30, 2022

Thematic School for Data Science in Sports Analytics.

# Volunteering

Intelligent User Interfaces 2023 I was a part of a volunteer team in the University of Sydney (Australia)

### ACHIEVEMENT

### Winner of NOI Hackathon SFSCON Edition.

Nov 12-13, 2021

Free Software Conference Hackathon. Our project: https://hackathon.bz.it/project/authpass

## Winner of NOI Hackathon Open Data Hub Edition.

May 20-21, 2022

Open Data Hub Hackathoin. My project: https://hackathon.bz.it/project/orange-juice

#### Winner of NOI Hackathon Summer Edition.

Aug 5-6, 2022

Summer Hackathon. Our project: https://hackathon.bz.it/project/octo-

### Winner of NOI Hackathon SFSCON Edition.

Nov 10-11, 2022

Free Software Conference Hackathon. Our project: https://hackathon.bz.it/project/procam

# REFERENCES

**Professor Mike Wald** Professor in the University of Southampton (email: m.wald@soton.ac.uk)

**Professor Jonathon Hare** Professor of Machine Learning in University of Southampton (email: jsh2@ecs.soton.ac.uk)

Last updated: May 24, 2023